Finding Aid for St. Matthew’s Episcopal Church (Flat Rock, Mich.) records, 1955-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
St. Matthew’s Episcopal Church (Flat Rock, Mich.) records 1955-2001
St. Matthew’s Episcopal Church (Flat Rock, Mich.).
1.25 linear feet
0695 Ba 2
St. Matthew’s Episcopal Church of Flat Rock, Michigan, member of the Episcopal Diocese of Michigan, was formed as a result of the unification of the Church of the Holy Family of East Rockwood and St. Timothy’s of Flat Rock and operated from 1971 to 2001; registers of baptisms, burials, confirmations, and marriages, and other organizational records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by the Episcopal Diocese of Michigan (donor no. 1059 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
St. Matthew's Episcopal Church of Flat Rock, Michigan, member of the Episcopal Diocese of Michigan, was formed as a result of the unification of the Church of the Holy Family of East Rockwood and St. Timothy's of Flat Rock. The church held services from 1971 to 2001.
The record group consists of two series: Historical and Genealogical materials and Organizational files. The record group is of most value for its documentation of church activities important to genealogical research.
Subjects:
Church of the Holy Family (Rockwood, Mich.); Episcopal Church--Michigan--Flat Rock.; St. Matthew's Episcopal Church (Flat Rock, Mich.); St. Timothy's Episcopal Church (Flat Rock, Mich.); Episcopal Church--Michigan--Rockwood.; Registers of births, etc.--Michigan--Flat Rock.; Flat Rock (Mich.)--Church history.; Rockwood (Mich.)--Church history.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Historical and Genealogical
  - Church Registers1955-2001, (incl. baptisms, confirmations, communicants, marriages, and burials) (Box 1)
    - Holy Family, 1955-1971, 2 volumes (Box 1)
    - St. Matthews, 1971-2001 (Box 1)
    - St. Timothy, 1957-1970 (Box 1)
  - Color Slides, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Gene E. Curry, Vicar, "Personal File," 1991 (Box 1)
  - Dedication / Groundbreaking of St. Matthew's Church, December 1973 (Box 1)
  - Membership List, ca. 1981 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1973-ca. 1985 (Box 1)
  - "St. Matthew's History," (Box 1)
    (incl. clippings, photographs, and a brief history written by Jack Ward)
- Organizational
  - Annual Reports 1971-1988, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Bishop's Committee Minutes, 1972-1993, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Grant Application, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Grant Requests (Box 1)
  - Parochial Reports, 1971-1994 (Box 1)
  - Proposed Budgets, 1972-1988 (Box 1)
  - Register of Church Services (incl. attendance counts)
    - Church of the Holy Family, 1955 and 1957-1971, 1 volume and 1 folder (Box 1)
    - St. Matthew's Episcopal Mission, 1971-1981 (Box 1)
    - St. Matthew's and St. Timothy's, 1970-1971 and 1982-1996 (Box 2)
    - St. Matthew's, 1996-2003 (Box 2)
    - St. Timothy's, 1956-1970 (Box 2)
  - Reports, Resolutions, Contracts, etc., ca. 1973-1976 (Box 2)
    (incl. a resolution regarding the priesthood and gender)
  - Total Expenses Tables, 2001 (Box 2)